if you're looking to add a new power
lifting bar to your home gym I
definitely recommend you take a close
look at the bells of Steel bare naked
power lifting bar 2.0 this bar has a
price tag of right around 220 bucks the
knurling is sharp as attack and you can
load up to 1500 pounds on it I've been
using this bar for a while now and I'm
really excited to tell you guys all
about it let's get right to it
[Music]
what's up y'all it's Jake back in the
barbin garage gym and this time around
we've got the bells of Steel bare naked
powerlifting bar 2.0 info review in this
video today I'm going to tell you
everything there is to know about this
barbell so we're going to talk about
some money we're going to talk about
some pros and cons but most importantly
we're going to talk about who should or
maybe should not purchase this barbell
now one more quick thing for them start
doing all that we reviewed a ton of
barbells on barbin.com and we went ahead
and made a best list of all of our top
choices that are on the market so if you
want to check that out all you do is
search barbin best barbells that list is
going to pull right up for you you can
find out for yourself which ones we like
the best
foreign
okay so just real quick you know for
those who don't know what a power
lifting bar is it's a barbell that is
you know specifically focused on the big
three of powerlifting which is squat
bench and deadlift so power lifting bar
is going to have no to you know minimal
spin in the loading sleeves it's going
to be you know more rigid more stiff
than an Olympic or a multi-purpose bar
and plus it's going to have a sharper
knurling than those you know bars I just
mentioned as well and you know those are
aspects you know traits that I've
noticed specifically with this bar right
here you know the knurling is like I
said sharp as attack I mean this barbell
is not going to slip out of your hands
as you're going to do a super heavy
deadlift which is something that you
definitely want to happen you go up to
1500 pounds on this bar which is plenty
strong for the majority of the fitness
Community pretty much everybody honestly
about 99 at least right it also has a
tension strength rating of 210 000 PSI
which for those who don't know what that
means it's essentially going to tell you
exactly how strong a barbell is and this
you know ranges on a spectrum of around
160 PSI up to sometimes 230 000 PSI 210
though is this is perfect for you know
what you're looking for right here
you're also going to get a limited
lifetime warranty with this barbell it's
going to cover any manufacturing defects
which is a nice thing right there plus
it's only going to cost you around 220
bucks which is you know as a why I said
earlier it's one of the best valued
powerlifting bars on the market but
because of that and that low price tag
is being driven by the fact that this is
a bare steel barbell so you're going to
have to clean it more frequently than
you will with any other bar out there
because this one is more prone to having
rust and corrosion forming on it than
any other bar that features any type of
coating
[Music]
all right so once again this barbell is
going to run you right around 220 bucks
honestly I think this is a super solid
price tag you know especially
considering what you're getting out of
it this knurling right here as I
mentioned sharpest attack you know it's
pulling off some skin right now just by
doing this and that's something that you
want you know with a power lifting bar
you know you have to worry about your
grip being compromised at all now it's
at least 100 cheaper than a lot of other
powerlifting bars that are of you know
similar quality but thing is you know
those are going to have you know some
type of coating whether it be Chrome
cerakote stainless steel whatever it is
that's what's kind of driving the price
tag up on those bars versus this one now
once again this is bare steel so you are
going to have to clean it a lot more
frequently than you will with a bar that
has a coating on it so you know if
you're somebody who doesn't want to do
that and you know take those extra you
know precautionary steps into preserving
this bar then it might be you know worth
spending an extra hundred dollars on a
power lifting bar that does have a
coating on it but to me you know at the
end of the day in the long run cleaning
it is not that bad it's not a very
detailed process and I think 220 is
honestly a bit of a steal for this
barbell
[Music]
so once again the shaft on this bar is
in fact bare steel so there's no coating
on it at all but the loading sleeves are
actually you know coated in Chrome
that's a nice thing it's going to help
protect the sleeves themselves you know
from rust incursion which is just pretty
cool and inside the sleeves right here
you're going to find bronze bushings you
know it's going to have a little bit of
a spin but nothing you know too crazy
it's not going to affect your power
lifts at all they're just there you do
have some grooves right here on the
loading sleeves and if you don't know
what those are they're designed to
specifically you know keep your bumper
plates in their original placement so
that's going to come in handy you know
as you're going to do your deadlifts you
drop the bar it's going to help keep
them from sliding down the sleeves and
you know kind of throwing off your lift
but you know definitely you still want
to use weight collars the knurling right
here it's super sharp I personally like
that it's a mountain style knurling so
all the neural markings right here kind
of point up like a mountain wood and
that's kind of leading to that sharpness
and I I like that you know if you sit
here and grip you know firm enough on
this bar you're going to notice markings
on your hand it's not crazy everybody's
gonna be crazy about that that's just
something that I personally like you
obviously you know you do have your
knurling right here in the middle that's
you know going to help you as you're
going to do your back squats it's going
to keep that bar on your upper back but
it's the same sharpness all across so
people might want to use a pad or maybe
even a towel or something up there on
your upper back definitely keep that in
mind once again you can load up to 1500
pounds on this bar and it has a tensile
strength rating of 210 000 PSI so this
bar is plenty strong to be put through
the ringer in the gym it's going to
suffice the needs of pretty much every
single athlete and then lastly you know
this is in fact a 20 kilogram bar it
measures 86.6 inches in length with 16.3
inch loading sleeves and the shaft has a
diameter of 29 millimeters so you know
that extra half a millimeter compared to
an Olympic Bar a multi-purpose bar it's
going to help fill up your palm and you
know increase that grip that you're able
to get
all right
[Music]
all right so as I like to do I'm going
to reiterate on some things here and
just kind of show you up close some
specs some of the details starting with
the loading sleeves you know once again
these are Chrome so they're going to
have a little bit of rust and Corrosion
Protection but you can kind of see the
the grooves right here that's you know
by Design to help keep your you know
weight plates locked into place but as
always you know get yourself some nice
weight collars and toss them on there to
help you out a little bit so another
thing I really like about this bar right
here with these loading sleeves is how
thin these collars are right here
they're at least an inch or so thinner
than pretty much every other most
barbells out there there's obviously
other ones like this as well but I like
that right there because it's especially
for people who are going to be loading
on a lot of weight you know it's going
to allow you to add more weight add an
extra 45 pound plate on there 25
whatever that's going to be good for you
as you can see you do have your bronze
bushings right here it's gonna you know
give you a little bit of that spin but
there's no need for spinning you know
that's just a standard with barbells
like this so move further on remember
this is bare Steel
there's mountain knurling right here
super grippy it's probably too sharp for
some people but
for for me specifically I really like it
especially with dead lifting which this
is actually our my favorite barbell to
deadlift with so that's going to be
really good for you you have your one
neural marking right here it's ipf
International powerlifting Federation
standard and that's to get identical
hand placement as you go to you know do
a wide grip lift with your bench press
now once again you do have the center
nerling right here it's super sharp it
is just as sharp as the rest of the
knurling right here so definitely keep
that in mind you know it might be a
little too sharp on your back as you go
to do a squat but you know it is what it
is and I personally don't have too much
of an issue with it
okay so not only do I think this is a
really solid option for anybody who's a
dedicated power lifter I also think this
is one of the best you know budget
friendly options you're going to get you
know the most bang for your buck in my
opinion with this barbell once again
it's only 220 bucks it's really hard to
beat that value but remember that's
because this is a bare steel bar you
know other than the loading sleeves this
is a bare steel bar so it's not going to
provide really any protection from rust
and corrosion so if you're somebody who
doesn't want to you know take those
extra precautionary steps and clean your
bar then I suggest spending you know an
extra 100 150 bucks on a bar that you
know is going to provide at least some
type of protection with the coating also
you know this is not designed for
anything other than power lifts so if
you're somebody who does like to you
know occasionally sprinkle in you know
your Olympic or CrossFit style lifts
then you definitely need to go after a
multi-purpose bar that can handle all of
it
foreign
for today's review over the bells of
Steel bare naked powerlifting bar 2.0
yes it's bare steel so it's going to be
prone to rust and corrosion from forming
but honestly that 220 price tag in my
opinion makes it well worth you know
taking that extra step to clean it plus
overall performance is is tough to beat
my opinion thanks for watching y'all
hope this video was helpful I was able
to answer any questions you have about
this barbell as always stay on the
lookout for my next video but for now
head over to barbin.com because we have
a full written review about this bar all
you gotta do is search bar Bend bells of
Steel bare naked powerlifting bar 2.0
review that article is going to pull
right up for you you can go over every
single thing we talked about here today
I'll catch y'all next time
foreign
[Music]